Welcome good to see you
欢迎，很高兴见到大家
Today we're going to begin a transitioning from
今天我们要转变一下研究内容
How a programs interact with hardware to how they interact with software in particular system software
从程序如何与硬件交互，以及它们如何与特定系统软件中的软件交互开始
And we're going to start that investigation by studying and learning about a process called linking
我们将通过研究和弄懂一个叫做链接的过程开始
Which is how the system builds your programs ok
这能帮助你好好弄清楚系统是如何构建你的程序
So we're going to study the process of linking
所以我们要学习链接的过程
And then I'm going to show you a really cool technique called library interpositioning
然后我将向你展示一项非常酷的技术，称为「库打桩」技术
Which allows you to use linking to actually intercept on function calls in libraries like the standard C library
这允许你使用链接实际拦截像 C 标准库这样的库中的函数调用
So it's a very powerful and interesting technique and it's all enabled by by linking
所以它是一种非常强大而且有趣的技术，它通过链接实现
So let's start with a simple program
让我们从一个非常简单的程序开始吧
This program consists of two modules a main.c and sum.c
这个程序里包含两个模块 main.c 和 sum.c
sum.c takes as an array as an argument and a length n
sum.c 将一个数组和一个长度 n 作为参数
And then it sums up the elements of that array and returns the sum  back to the caller
然后它计算了该数组中元素的总和并将总和返回给调用者
main.c calls the sum function
main.c 调用了 sum 函数
Using and passes it a two element array of ints
使用并传递一个两元素的 int 类型数组
And then returns the value received from some
然后返回了从其中收到的值
Yeah we that that's kind of an odd thing to do to return your exit status like that
是的，我们认为像这样返回退出状态是件奇怪的事情
But we just did it so that the compiler wouldn't optimize away all of a code
但我们这样做，以便编译器不会优化掉所有代码
I know let's look at what happens if when we want to compile those those two modules
让我们来看看如果我们想要编译那两个模块会发生什么
For each of main.c and sum.c
对于每个 main.c 和 sum.c
The GCC calls a series of translators on that,on those modules,on those .c files
GCC 会在这些模块上调用 .c 文件上的一系列翻译器
First calls the C preprocessor cpp
首先调用 C 预处理器 cpp(将 main.c 翻译成 ASCII 中间文件 main.i)
Then it calls the compiler,the actual compiler which is cc1
然后它调用编译器，实际上使用的编译器是叫 cc1(将 main.i 翻译成 ASCII 汇编语言文件 main.s)
The compiler generates assembly which is then translated by the assembler as
编译器生成汇编程序，然后汇编器将其翻译
And resulting in a .o file called main.o
结果生成了一个 .o 文件，称为 main.o
Similar things happens for sum.c
sum.c 也发生了类似的事情
So after these three translators work on the code
在这三个翻译器处理完代码之后
We have two object files two .o files
生成了两个 .o 格式目标文件
The linker takes those those .o files
链接器取到这些 .o 格式目标文件
And put some,links them together sort of smashes them together to form a single executable called that we can then run
将它们拼凑在一起，创建一个单个的可执行文件然后运行
然后放一些（必要的系统目标文件），将它们链接在一起，
Then we can then load and run on the system
然后我们就可以加载并运行到系统上
So the main.c and sum.c they are called source files
所以 main.c 和 sum.c 被称为源文件
These .o files are object files that
这些 .o 文件
We are separately compiled
虽然是我们分开编译的目标文件
But we call them relocatable object files
但我们还是要叫他们可重定位目标文件
Because they can be combined together to form the fully linked executable object file
因为它们可以组合在一起形成完全链接的可执行目标文件
So why do we do it like this, you know why do we allow this so-called separate compilation
那为什么我们这样做呢，你知道为什么我们允许这种所谓的分离编译
You know why don't we just have like one big you know one big file that with all of code in it
你知道为什么我们不喜欢一个包含所有代码的大文件
Well there's a couple reasons the first is is modularity so by allowing you to break your code into smaller pieces
有一些原因，首先是模块化，允许你将代码分解成更小的部分
You can put related functions into separate source files
你可以将相关功能放入单独的源文件中
You can define libraries of functions
你可以定义函数库
So it's just good technique and it allows you to kind of break your code up into nice modular pieces
所以这只是一种很好的技术，它可以让你将代码分解成很好的模块化的部分
The other reason is efficiency
另一个理由是效率
So if we've broken up our program into multiple chunks
所以如果我们把我们的程序分为多个块
If we change and if we only need to change one of the chunks
当我们改变，比如我们只需要更改其中一个块
We don't have to recompile the all the other modules
我们就没必要重新编译所有其他模块
Right we can just recompile the one module that we changed and then link them all together again
对，我们可以重新编译我们更改的一个模块，然后再将它们全部链接在一起
Right so it's efficient in time it's also efficient in space
所以这在时间和空间上都是有效的
Because you can take all of the functions in the standard C library you could put them all together
因为你可以使用 C 标准库中的所有功能，所以你可以将它们放在一起
But then the only functions that you actually get compiled and linked into your program are the ones that you actually call
但是，实际编译并链接到程序中的唯一函数是你实际调用的函数
Ok so you can save space
好的，这样你就可以节省空间
You don't you know normally you use only a small subset of the standard C functions
你通常不知道你其实只使用 C 标准函数的一小部分
So there's no point in linking all of those functions into your code if you don't need them
因此，如果你不需要将所有这些功能链接到代码中，那就没有意义了
Alright so what do linkers do
好吧，那么链接器做了什么呢
Well there's two main tasks that a linker performs
链接器执行的主要任务有两个
The first is called simple resolution
第一个被称为简单解析（符号解析）
So programs define and reference symbols
程序会定义和引用符号
Okay that what the linker refers to as symbols and these are global variables and functions
好的，链接器称为符号，这些是全局变量和函数
Okay in the names and those objects they're referred to as a symbol
在名称和那些对象中，它们被称为符号
So here we're declaring,we're defining a symbol called swap
第一行代码，我们在这里声明，我们正在定义一个名为 swap 的符号
Here we're referring when we call swap, we're referring to that symbol
中间这行我们称之为 swap，我们指的是那个符号
Okay that's a reference to the symbol
是的，这是对符号的一种引用
And here we're defining a pointer to an int called xp
最后一行，我们定义了一个指向名为 xp 的 int 类型指针
So we're defining xp and we're initializing it to the address of x
所以我们定义了 xp ，将它初始化为取 x 的地址
So we're referring,that's a reference to x
这指的是，这是对 x 的引用
Okay so the symbol definitions are stored in the object file by the assembler
汇编器将符号定义存储在目标文件中
In a symbol table which is an array of structs
在这个符号表里面，全是一系列结构数组
Where each structs contains information about the symbol
每个结构数组里面包含有关该符号的信息
Like the name of the symbol its size and where it's located
比如符号的名称，它的大小和位置等等信息
Now what we mean by symbol resolution is that during the linker linking process
所以现在我们说符号解析的意思是在链接器链接过程中
The linker associates each symbol reference with exactly one symbol definition
链接器将每个符号引用与一个符号定义相关联
Okay so it's possible in multiple
好的，所以这可能有多个
You know why is this an issue well it's possible like in multiple modules
这中间可能会有些问题，比如在多个模块中
You may declare a global variable with the same name
你可能会声明一个有相同名称的全局变量
The linker has to decide which one of those definitions to use for all subsequent references
链接器必须决定将其中的某个定义用于所有后续引用
Now once the linker is associated a unique object
一旦链接器和一个独一无二的目标建立联系
With each a unique symbol definition with each reference
每个引用都会有一个唯一的符号定义
Then it does the second step which is relocation
然后它执行第二步，即重定位
And during relocation it merges all of the modules together
在重定位期间，它会将所有模块合并在一起
Into a single executable object module that can be directly loaded and executed on the system
进入单个可执行目标模块后，就可以直接在系统上加载和执行
So when it does this merging
所以当它合并时
It has to figure out where each symbol,each function and each variable is going to be stored
它必须弄清楚每个符号，每个函数和每个变量是要准备存储在哪
And this is called relocation
这称为重定位
Because initially functions are just stored at some offset in their object module
因为最初的函数只是存储在其目标模块中的某个偏移处
Right because that the linker doesn't know where those functions are actually going to be eventually a loaded into memory
正确，因为链接器不知道这些函数最终会被真正加载到内存中的哪个地方
So before relocation the address of a function in the object module is just its offset in the module and similarly for data
所以在重定向前目标模块中的函数地址只是它在模块中的偏移量，对于数据也是如此
During the relocation step the linker decides on
在重定位步骤期间，链接器会决定
Where each symbol is going to be ultimately located in memory one at x,when the program executes
当程序执行时，每个符号最终将位于 x 中的存储区中的哪里
And it binds that those absolute memory locations to the symbol
并且它将那些绝对存储器位置绑定到符号
And then it goes and looks at all the references to those symbols
然后它会继续向下执行并查看所有对这些符号的引用
And it updates those references so that they now they point to the correct address
而且它们会更新那些引用，以便它们现在能指向正确的地址
Okay so figure out where stuff is going to go
好的，所以弄清楚原料要去哪里
For each definition figure out where it's going to go and for each reference then update that reference
对于每个定义，找出它要去的位置以及每个引用，然后更新该引用
So it now points to the right spot
所以它现在指向正确的位置
So let's look at what these...how these steps work in more detail
那么让我们来看看这些......这些步骤如何更详细地运作
Before that we need to define a few things
在那之前我们需要定义一些东西
So there's three kinds of object modules that I've alluded to
所以我提到了三种目标模块
There's the .o file which is a relocatable object module this is the output of the assembler
.o 文件是可重定位目标模块，这是汇编器的输出
And it's not a binary file
它不是一个二进制文件
But it's not in any form that can be directly loaded into memory
但它不能以任何形式直接加载到内存中
It needs to be manipulated by the linker before it can be actually used
在实际使用之前，需要由链接器对其进行操作
There's the executable object file which is generated by the linker
由链接器生成的可执行目标文件
These is called a.out files
这被称为 a.out 文件
Sometimes historically the very first Linux systems the executable
在历史上第一个 Linux 操作系统就是可执行的
This sort of the default name that they the developers of Unix used,the default name for their executables was a.out
这是 Unix 开发人员使用的默认名称，其可执行文件的默认名称是 a.out
So that's just sort of a historical reason that it's called a.out
所以这只是一个历史原因所以它被称为 a.out
And then there's another type of object file called a shared object file or .so file
然后是另一种称为共享目标文件或 .so 文件的目标文件
Which is a modern technique for creating shared libraries
这是一种用于创建共享库的现代技术
And we'll look at those,we'll look at those later today
那个我们之后再了解，将在今天晚些时候再学习了解
Now object modules come in a standard format called ELF format
现在，目标模块采用称为 ELF 格式的标准格式
And it's a unified format for .o files for executables and for .so files
它是可执行文件，.so 文件，.o 文件的统一格式
They all use the same format,the same general format
他们都使用一样的格式，一样的通用的格式
So this while these ELF binaries are
这就是这些 ELF 二进制文件
Their binaries they're very structured
他们的二进制文件非常有条理
Ok and they're broken up into sections
他们被分成几个部分
The at the beginning is a header,that defines things like the size of the word the byte ordering
开头是一个头，它定义了（生成该文件系统的）字节顺序和字的大小
Whether it's a .o,a .out or a .so
无论是 .o, .out 还是 .so
So it just provides some sort of general information about this binary
它只是提供了关于这个二进制文件的一般信息
And then there's what's a so called segment header table which is
然后就是所谓的节头部表
It's only defined for the executable object files
它只在可执行目标文件中定义
And indicates where all the different segments of the code are going to go in memory
并指出代码的所有不同段在内存中的位置
So where does your stack go, where do your shared libraries go
那么你的栈在哪里，你的共享库去了哪里
Where does your that you're initialized and uninitialized data
你初始化数据和未初始化数据的位置在哪里
Where does your code go
你的代码去了哪里
Right so all these various sections are defined in the segment header table
正确，因此所有这些不同的部分都在段头表中定义
And then there's the code itself which is called the .text section for sort of arcane historical reasons
然后是代码本身，出于某种神秘的历史原因它被称为 .text 部分
So .text is always code
.text 一般是代码
And then that's followed by read only data
然后是只读数据
Such as the jump tables in switch statements
比如 switch 语句中的跳转表
So text and read only the .text and .rodata have the property that they're both read-only you don't write to them
因此，文本 .text 和只读 .rodata 具有以下属性：它们都是只读的，你不会写入它们
Then that's followed by the .data section
然后是 .data 部分
Which is contains space for all of your initialized global variables
它包含了所有初始化全局变量的空间
And then there's a section called .bss
接下来是一个名为 .bss 的部分
Which defines the uninitialized global variables
它定义了未初始化的全局变量
Now this doesn't actually take up any space because they're uninitialized droids
这个节实际上并没有占用任何实际的空间，因为它们仅仅是未初始化的占位符
Ok but there are entries in the symbol table for them
好的，但符号表中会有条目
And in it at when this program gets loaded these variables are going to need
在这个程序加载时会需要这些变量
They're actually going to have to have space allocated for them
在这个时候就必须为他们分配空间
.bss is another one of those sort of arcane names,that cope goes all the way back to the 60s
.bss 是另一种神秘的名字，应对可以追溯到 60 年代
For there was IBM instruction called the block started by symbol
那时候 IBM 指令将其称为块符号
I think a better way to remember what it means is better save space
我认为理解它的意义最好的方式是 better save space (BSS) 的缩写
Ok so you can,if you have a separate section for the uninitialized variable since uninitialized
好的，如果在未初始化过程开始时有一个单独的节用于未初始化的变量，你可以这样理解
You don't have to...they don't have to consume any room in the .o file
他们不必占用 .o 文件中的任何空间
Ok there's also a section for the symbol table
好的接下来还有一个部分是针对符号表的
This contained like I said it's an array of structs for procedures global variables
就像我之前说的那样它包含程序全局变量的结构数组
And anything defined with the static attribute
以及我们使用 static 属性定义的任何内容
And each one of these symbols gets an entry in the symbol table
并且这些符号中的每一个都在符号表中获得了一个条目
And then there's two sections called them that contain relocation info so this is the notes
然后有两个部分称为包含重定位信息的部分，称为记录
When that linker went and identified all the references to symbols it put a little note to see
当链接器去识别所有对符号的引用时，它就会记下一些记录
I'm going to have to remember to fix this the reference to this symbol up
我不得不记住去安排对这个符号的引用
When I actually create the executable
在我实际创建可执行文件时
So a relocation entry is just like that the linker
所以重定向条目就像链接器一样
That it's a note that the assembler makes to the linker to say hey you're going to have to fix up this this reference
这是一个记录，汇编程序让链接器说「嘿」，你将不得不安排这个引用
Because I don't know I don't know where this symbol is actually going to be stored in memory when it's loaded
因为我不知道这个符号在加载时实际存储在内存中的位置
Okay and then there's a debug section that contains
好的，接下来是调试部分
Information that relates line numbers to in the source code to line numbers in the machine code
它包含了将源代码中的行号与机器代码中的行号相关联的信息
Okay and so this is called .debug and this is what you get when you compile with -g
好的，所以这叫做 .debug，这是你用-g编译时得到的
And then there's a header table that tells you where all these different sections start
然后有一个节头表，告诉你所有这些不同部分的起始位置
Now to a linker there's three different kinds of symbols
现在我们说链接器有三种不同的符号
Global symbols are defined in some module m
全局符号在一些模块 m 中定义
And they can be used by other modules
它们可以被其他模块使用
Right so I mean did you notice when we...if we have a program that consists of multiple modules
是的，所以我的意思是你注意到我们......如果我们有一个由多个模块组成的程序
And we compile each one of those modules into a .o file
然后我们将每个模块编译成一个 .o 文件
Will be calling functions that aren't defined,that are defined by other modules right
将调用由其他模块正确定义的未定义的函数
Okay so those,but there's no error though that the compiler doesn't throw an error
好吧那些，但是虽然编译器没有抛出错误
Because it's assuming that those are defined in other modules and
因为它假设那些是在其他模块中定义的
It assumes the linker will be able to find them in and determine the address
它假定链接器能够找到它们并确定地址
So anything that's defined with that, any global,either global variable or function name
所以用任何全局变量或函数名定义的任何东西
That's defined without the static attribute is a global symbol
只要没有静态属性的定义那就是一个全局符号
Okay now and then external symbols are kind of the flip side of that
好的，然后外部符号就是其中的一种
External symbols are symbols that are referenced by some module
外部符号是某些模块引用的符号
But defined in some other module
但在其他一些模块中定义
Okay so in a little running example
好吧，在这个小运行示例中
When main.c code called the function some it was referencing an external symbol
当 main.c 代码调用函数时，它就会引用了一个外部符号
Okay and then there's local symbols and these are symbols that are defined and referenced within a module
好的，接下来我们介绍局部符号，这是在模块中定义和引用的符号
Okay and those you create that,this is not this is different from local variables
好的，那些是你创建的（程序里面的变量），它不同于局部变量
Okay the linker you know local C variables are managed by the compiler on the stack
好的，你知道的，局部 C 程序变量的链接器是由堆栈上的编译器管理的
Linker has no idea about local C variables
链接器它是不知道局部 C 程序的变量的
Okay in this context when we talk about a local symbol
好的，在这种情况下当我们谈到一个局部符号
We're talking about is either, is a global variable or function declared with the static attribute
实际上我们讨论的是，一个全局变量或用 static 属性声明的函数
Whose that can only be referenced from within that module
那玩意只能从该模块中引用它
So we say that the scope of the a function or global variable defined with the static
所以我们说用 static 属性定义的函数或全局变量
Attribute is limited to the module that it was defined in
其范围仅限于其定义的模块
Okay so this is in C, this is how we do abstraction
好的，这就是在 C 语言里 ，这就是我们怎么进行抽象
And this is how we can create sort of private functions that
以及这就是我们如何创建私有函数
And private functions that can't be called from outside that module
并且是无法从该模块外部调用的私有函数
Okay so for instance if we want to make a library in C of functions, we want to make a collection of functions that
好的，例如，如果我们想在函数 C 中创建一个库，我们想要创建一个函数集合
Other programs can then call it link into their program and call
其他程序可以将其称为链接到他们程序和调用
The functions that we want to make visible to other programs are defined without the static attribute
我们希望对其他程序可见的函数是在没有加上 static 属性定义的
And the functions that we want to have private and just be internal
我们希望只是对于内部而言的
We declare what the static attribute okay
我们声明 static 属性
And that way we get abstraction and we get hiding information hiding
这样我们就可以抽象，并将我们希望隐藏的信息隐藏
And we're only exposing data and functions that we want to expose
我们只展示我们想要公开的数据和功能
All right so let's look in detail how the symbol resolution step works
好的，接下来让我们详细了解符号解析步骤的工作原理
We call a example program
我们来拜访一下这个例子程序
So here we're referencing a global called array
这里我们引用了一个全局调用数组
That's defined within main.c
这个在 main.c 中定义
Here we're defining main
在这里，我们定义了 main 函数
A global called main
一个全局调用 main 函数
Here we're referencing a global called sum
在这里，我们引用一个全局调用 sum 函数
That's defined in sum.c
它定义在 sum.c 中间
And val is a local C variable on the stack and linker knows nothing about that okay
val 是堆栈上的局部 C 变量，链接器实际上对其没有任何了解
Now loads i, s which are also local variables
现在加载 i，s, 当然这两者也是局部变量
Now let's make sure that we understand the difference between local static C variables versus local non static C variables so
现在让我们确保我们理解了局部 static C 变量与本地非 static C 变量之间的区别
Here we're defining a local static variable called int
这里我们定义一个类型为 int 的局部静态变量
Within this function f
在这个函数 f 中
Now because it's local, its scope is limited to this function
现在因为它是的局部，它的范围仅限于此功能
So this variable x can only be referenced within function f
所以这个变量 x 只能在函数 f 中引用
And similarly for this definition of x in function g
类似于函数 g 中 x 的这个定义
Can only be referenced by function g
只能被函数 g 引用
Now what's ,but because it's declared with the static attribute it's not stored on the stack
它是什么样的，但因为它是用静态属性声明的，所以它不存储在堆栈中
It's actually stored in .data just like a global would be
它实际上存储在 .data 文件中，就像全局变量一样
So it's like a global in the sense that it's actually stored in .data rather than the stack
所以它就像一个实际上存储在 .data 而不是堆栈中的全局变量
But it's like a local C variable in the sense that its scope is limited just to the function that it's defined in
但它就像一个局部 C 程序变量，因为它的范围仅限于它所定义的函数
Okay so what the compiler will do it'll allocate space for each definition of x
好的，那么编译器会做什么呢，它将为每个 x 的定义分配空间
So this and it'll give it some name to disambiguate it
所以这样的话，它会给它赋予一些名称来消除它的歧义
So maybe it will call this one x.1
所以也许它会称之为 x.1
And maybe this one x.2
也有可能叫 x.2
So these symbols are allocated in .data because
这些符号分配在在 .data 中，因为
Because they're initialized and they get symbol table entries just like any other symbol
因为它们已初始化并且像任何其他符号一样会获得符号表条目
Okay so I said that during symbol resolution
好的，所以我在讲解符号解析期间说过
The linker associates each reference,each symbol reference to exactly one unique symbol definition
链接器和每个引用连接起来，每个符号引用与一个唯一的符号定义相关联
Now how does it do that if there's multiple symbol definitions across all the modules
现在有一种情况，如果所有模块中有多个符号定义，它是如何做的呢
So to understand this will define symbols as being either strong or weak
因此，要理解这种情况需要将把符号定义为强或弱
So strong symbols are either procedures or function names or initialize global variables
过程，函数名称或已初始化的全局变量是强符号
Weak symbols are uninitialized global variables
弱符号是未初始化的全局变量
Okay so int foo here is a strong symbol
好吧，所以这里的 int foo 是一个强有力的象征
Because it's initialized,we're initializing it. p1 is strong by definition
因为它已初始化，我们正在初始化它。根据定义，p1 是强符号
foo is weak in p2.c, this definition of foo is weak
p2.c 中的 foo 就是弱符号，这个定义的 foo 就是弱符号
Because it's uninitialized and the definition of p2 is strong
因为它没有初始化，下面这个 p2 的定义的话就是强符号
Okay so that the rules, the linker uses are the following
好的，链接器使用的规则如下
Multiple strong symbols not allowed so that's an error
不允许有多个强符号，以免出现错误
Okay so that means that if across multiple modules we declare a function with the same name
好的，这意味着如果我们在多个模块中，声明一个具有相同名称的函数
The linker will throw an error that's not allowed
链接器将抛出一个不允许的错误
Given a strong symbol and multiple weak symbols if the linker will always choose the the strong symbol
如果链接器总是选择强符号，则给出强符号和多个弱符号
Now remember if we initialize a global variable
现在记住我们是否初始化了一个同名的全局变量
And we if we declare an initialized global variable across multiple modules that's an error
如果我们在多个模块中声明一个同名的初始化的全局变量，那么我们就是一个错误
Because those are strong symbols okay by rule one
因为那些是强符号的第一条规则
But if we have one strong symbol and multiple weak symbols all with the same name
但是如果我们有一个强符号和多个弱符号具有相同的名称
Then the compiler will choose the strong symbol
然后编译器将选择强符号
Okay and it will associate all references to that symbol will go to that strong symbol
好的，它将所有对该符号的引用关联到该强符号
And if there's multiple weak symbols then it just picks an arbitrary one
如果有多个弱符号同名，那么它会从这些弱符号中任意选择一个
And this is we'll see can be problematic now you can override with this GCC flag called no common
这是我们将看到的，可能会有问题，现在你可以用这个名为 no common 的 GCC 标志覆盖
And if you declare your function with this no common argument
如果你用这个 no common 的参数声明函数
Then multiple weak symbols will throw an error in a linker
然后多个弱符号将在链接器中抛出错误
All right so why do we care about all this stuff well it turns out
好吧，为什么我们关心所有这些东西呢
If you're not aware of this stuff you can run into some really serious problems
如果你不了解这些东西，你可能会遇到一些非常严重的问题
That are just perplexing and confounding right so
这些东西容易令人困惑和混淆
Linker errors are like the worst kind
链接器错误就是最糟糕的那种
They're the hardest kind of debug because people aren't usually aware of what's going on inside their linkers
它们是最难调试的，因为人们通常不知道链接器的内部发生了什么
And usually it's only like the very best programmers that really understand
而且通常只有最好的程序员真的理解里面发生了什么
You know how these linkers work and what kind of errors they can throw and how to debug them
你知道这些链接器是如何工作的，它们可以抛出什么样的错误以及如何调试它们
So let me show you some examples of these kind of errors
那么让我向你展示一些这类错误的例子
All right so we have a program
好的，我们有一个程序
We have two modules so each of these rectangles corresponds to a module
我们有两个模块，这里每个矩形窗口对应一个模块
And we're defining p1 in each module so
我们在每个模块中定义 p1
That's two strong symbols that's an error
这里有两个强符号，因此出现了错误
Okay now here we've defining p1 and p2 so we're okay
好的，现在我们已经定义了 p1 和 p2，这没有问题
But now we've got two weak symbols both are integers variables called x
但现在我们有两个弱符号，都是整数变量，称为 x
So and if these modules are referencing x the linker will just pick it will just pick one of these to serve as the definition
因此，如果这些模块引用 x，链接器将只选择其中一个作为定义
But is this really what you want
但这真的是你想要的结果吗
Now in this case it doesn't really hurt anything because x is declared in both modules as an int
现在在这种情况下它并没有什么影响，因为 x 在两个模块中都被声明为 int
All right so it'll just be some integer sized variable
所以它只是一个整数大小的变量
That and it'll be somewhere
它将在某个地方放着
And but it doesn't really matter which one the linker chooses
但是链接器选择哪一个并不重要
But we start to get into trouble if we declare these weak symbols with different types
但是如果我们用不同的类型声明这些弱符号，我们就遇到麻烦了
So here we've declared an int x in one module and a double x in another module
在这里，我们在一个模块中声明了一个 int x，在另一个模块中声明了一个 double x
So if we write to x, if the linker just arbitrarily chooses this,this symbol definition to use
当我们写入 x 时，如果链接器随意选择了这个，那么就使用此符号定义
Now this is a symbol that of length 8 of size 8
这是长度为 8 的符号
If we anywhere in this program,if the linker chooses that then, anywhere in the program
如果我们在这个程序中的任何地方，如果链接器选择程序中的任意地方
Those references to x will be to this double word,this double word
那些对 x 的引用将是这个双字，这个双字
Even in this module if we reference x it'll be an 8-byte right
即使在这个模块中，如果我们引用 x，它也将是一个 8 字节的
So it will overwrite y with the
所以它会覆盖 y
Hi order excuse me
你有什么问题吗
[student speaking]
[学生在发言...]
Oh no it's completely,it's just pick one arbitrarily
噢它不完全是这样，它只是任意选择一个
And you don't know
而且你不知道
I mean it
我的意思是
Now this is here's a problem we've defined a strong symbol x because we've initializes
现在这是一个问题，我们已经定义了一个强符号x，因为我们已经初始化了
So the linker will always,will associate all references to x to this integer sized this integer sized symbol
因此链接器将始终将对x的所有引用与此整数大小符号相关联
So if we write
所以，如果我们写
Oh yeah right,so rights to x here
哦是的，对于 x
This will be a double in this module but it will overwrite y in this module
这将是此模块中的两倍，但它将覆盖此模块中的 y
So that's really nasty
所以那真的很讨厌
And here we were defining a strong symbol x
在这我们正在定义一个强符号 x
So references to x in the second module will always get it will refer to this initialized variable which might not
因此，在第二个模块中对x的引用的结果将得到它将引用这个初始化的变量
So it might not be what you want right
所以它可能不是你想要的
You may be assuming that it's uninitialized in your code
你可能认为它在你的代码中未初始化
Okay and then you get the, the ultimate nightmare scenario is suppose
好吧，然后你得到了，最终的噩梦场景就是，假设...嗯
You know because we're following a standard ABI we can compile our code with multiple compilers
你知道，因为我们遵循标准的 ABI，我们可以用多个编译器编译我们的代码
And this actually happens in some , oh yes questions
这实际上发生在一些，嗯好的请你提问
[student speaking]
[学生在发言]
Oh yeah actually you're right
嗯是的你说的是对的
It will still take preference and and you'll be writing a for by quantity
它仍然会优先考虑并且你将按数量编写
Which is what you want so that slides not quite right
这是你想的，所以那个幻灯片上的不太正确
So oh yeah what is the point of doing the static versus non static
（学生）所以哦，是的，处理静态与非静态的重点是什么
If it's always being referenced just locally in constantly what is the point of declaring  it's time
（学生）如果它总是不断的在被本地引用，那么什么是宣布它时间的点
-is it it stores it in like -no no no it's
（学生）是不是该把他存储起来  （教授）不不不，不是的
If you reference up if you reference a variable
如果引用变量，就会引用
You mean so a variable is defined in your module
你的意思是在模块中定义一个变量
And then you...with the static...right
然后你....用 static....对吗
Oh they're both,they're both local
噢，他们都是，他们都是局部的
So you do this if you want to value two to retain
因此，如果你想要保留两个值，请执行此操作
From if you want if you want that variable to retain value from invocation to invocation
如果你想要该变量保留从调用到调用的值
So suppose you it's usually a bad idea as we'll see when we study threads
所以假设你，这通常是一个坏主意，因为我们会在研究线程时看到
Because it makes your code non thread safe
因为这将使你的代码线程不安全
But like early like random number generators
但就像早期的随机数生成器一样
Would it would compute a pseudo-random number
它会计算一个伪随机数
And then it would store it in a static variable
然后它会存储在一个静态变量里面
And then use that as the the starting value for the next time you call that function
然后将其用作下次调用该函数时的起始值
So whenever you want values to persist across function invocation to reduce static
因此，无论何时你都希望值能被允许进行跨越函数调用以减少静态
Yes something really crash
（学生）某些事情真的崩溃了
Well wait a minute let me...
等一下让我...
Let me get this straight writes to x and p2 will actually correspond to the memory
让我直接写入 x 和 p2， 这实际上将和内存链接起来
Look that it will actually go to the memory location I'm sorry I need to amend that
看它实际上会进入内存位置，我很抱歉我需要修改它
So writes to x in p2 will be 8 bytes
因此，在 p2 中写入 x 将是 8 个字节
Because the compiler you know the compiler knows that it's a double
因为编译器，你知道编译器会知道它是双精度的
But it'll go to a memory location that's only 4 bytes
但它会进入一个只有 4 个字节的内存位置
Because x because the linker chose the strong symbol
因为 x...因为链接器选择了强符号
Okay so the rights to x and p2 will actually overwrite y
好的，正确的是 x 和 p2 实际上会覆盖 y
I'm sorry yes question
对不起...好的，有人有问题
[student speaking]
[学生发言]
That's just usually the way it happens
它通常就是这样发生的
You know...[student speaking]
你知道...... [学生说话]
No no no global variables go in data they don't go on the stack
不不不全局变量进入了数据，他们并没有进栈
But usually if you define local variables in a function
但通常来说，如果你在函数中定义局部变量
It will put them,it will allocate them one after the other on the stack
它会放置它们，它会将他们一个接一个地分配到栈上
Okay all right so all this discussion about
好的，所有这些讨论
These weird strong weak symbol rules that the linker have
有关链接器具有的这些奇怪的强弱符号规则
It's another reason to avoid global variables if you can
这是避免全局变量的另一个原因
Now if you need to declare a global see if you can declare it static
现在，如果你需要声明全局变量，请看看是否可以将其声明为 static
Because that'll limited scope to the the module that it's declared in
因为那样会限制了它声明的模块的范围
So that's a good idea if you can do it
如果你那样做的话，是个好主意
And if you define a global variable initialize it
如果你定义了一个全局变量，就把它初始化了
So that you'll find,you'll discover if you have multiple initialize global symbols with the same name in your code
所以你会发现，你会发现你的代码中是否有多个具有相同名称的初始化全局符号
And then if you want to it's always good practice
如果你想要，它总是好的做法
If you're referencing an external variable to tell the compiler about it by using the extern attribute
如果你正在引用外部变量，则通过使用 extern 属性告诉编译器
All right
好的
So now at this point the linker has associated every symbol reference  with some simple definition
所以现在，链接器已经将每个符号引用与一些简单的定义相关联
Now it has to take all those object relocatable object files and smush them together
现在它必须获取所有这些对象可重定位目标文件并将它们组合在一起
And create like one big executable
并创建一个大的可执行文件
So suppose with our example a little running example
因此，假设我们拿一个小运行示例来举例
Each main.o and sum.o contain a code and initialize data
每个 main.o 和 sum.o 都包含了代码并初始化数据
sum.o doesn't have any initialize data it just has code
sum.o 没有初始化数据，只有代码
And then there's their system code that actually runs before and after your program so
然后是上面的系统代码，它实际上在你的程序之前和之后运行
When your program run it actually starts executing a startup code from  from lib.c
程序运行时，它从 lib.c 开始执行启动代码
That that sort of initializes things and then the last thing that it does is it calls main and passes it rc and rv
它主要做这一类初始化的事情，然后它做的最后一件事是它调用 main 并传递 rc 和 rv
Okay and then when you're, when your program exits
好的，然后当你的程序退出时
Well that's a cyst call,but if your program if your main function routine does a return
会有一个调用，但如果你的程序...如果你的主函数例程返回
Then it returns back to that startup code which then doesn't exit okay
然后它返回到那个启动代码，然后没退出
So this is just...so this this consists of of text and data as well
这包括文本和数据
And so when the linker relocates these object files
所以当链接器重定位这些目标文件时
It takes all of the code the text sections from each of the modules
它将所有代码都放在每个模块的文本部分中
And puts them together contiguously init in the .text section for the executable object file
并将它们连续地放在可执行对象文件的 .text 部分中
Ok so it just puts them together in some order that it determines
它只是按照它确定的顺序将它们组合在一起
And it creates a combined .text section in the executable
它在可执行文件中创建了一个组合的 .text 部分
That contains all of the system code and the all of the all of the code defined in the modules
它包含所有系统代码和模块中定义的所有代码
And then it does the same thing with the data takes all the .data
然后它会对数据采用所有 .data 做同样的事情
Sections from the various object files and puts them together
来自各种目标文件的部分并将它们放在一起
In one combined .data section in the executable
在可执行文件中的一个组合的 .data 部分
And it also emerges the symbol tables and in the debug information as well
它还会出现符号表和调试信息
Now when it just the act the act of sort of
现在当它起作用
Relocating these object files requires the linker
重定向这些目标文件需要链接器
To figure out where it's going to actually store these
来弄清楚它们实际存储在哪里
These different these different symbols when the system gets, when this program gets loaded
当程序加载时，这些不同的符号...
So it has to pick an address for main that
所以它必须为 main 选择一个地址
That function will start at some absolute address
以至于函数将从某个绝对地址开始
It's going to have... it's going to do the same for swap,so for all the all the data arrays right
它会对 swap() 做同样的事情，以保证所有数组都是正确的
And but the problem is that when this code is compiled,the compiler doesn't know what addresses the linker is going to pick
但问题是，当编译此代码时，编译器不知道链接器将选择哪些地址
So the compiler creates these reminders to the linker called relocation entries
因此，编译器会向称为重定位条目的链接器创建这些提醒
Which are then stored in the relocation sections of the the object file
然后将其存储在目标文件的重定位部分中
And these relocation entries are instructions to the linker that's something
这些重定位条目是链接器的指令
That there's a reference to a symbol that's going to have to be patched up
有一个符号的引用必须要修改
When the the code is actually relocated and merged into the executable
在代码实际重定位并合并到可执行文件中时
So let's look at a couple of these a couple of examples so in
让我们看看其中的几个例子
Our in our main.c module there was a reference to this global symbol called array
我们在 main.c 模块中引用了一个名为 array 的全局符号
Okay and then there was also a reference to this global symbol sum which is the function
好的，然后还有一个引用，全局符号 sum， 这是一个函数
So the compiler creates two relocation entries
因此编译器会创建两个重定位条目
The first one for the reference to the array a
第一个用于引用数组 a
So here we're moving member %edi is the first argument
所以这里我们正在传送的成员 ％edi 是第一个参数
So remember a sum function takes the address of the of array
所以请记住 sum 函数获取数组的地址
Of the input array as its argument
输入数组作为其参数
So this move we're moving the address of the array into %edi for the first argument
因此，我们将第一个参数的数组地址传送到 ％edi 中
But the compiler doesn't know what that address is going to be
但编译器不知道该地址会是什么
Right so it just it just it just
是的，它只是...
It just moves in an immediate value of 0 into %edi temporarily right so you can see this is all zeros
它只是暂时把立即数值 $0x0 传送到 ％edi ，所以你可以看到这是全零
The bf is the mov instruction and then there's all zeros for now
bf 是 mov 指令，然后后面全都是 0
And then it places this relocation entry in the relocation section of main.o
然后它将此重定位条目放在 main.o 的重定位部分中
And it says to the linker at offset a
它在偏移量 a 处告知链接器
So these let me remind you these are main.o
所以这些提醒你们这些是 main.o 模块
Module only contains one function
这个模块只包含一个函数
So that function starts that offsets zero in the code section of the module in the .text section of the module
因此，该函数在模块的 .text 部分的模块的代码部分偏移为零的地方开始
If there were other functions in this module they would follow immediately after
如果此模块中还有其他功能，则会立即跟进
Ok and it so you can see what the compiler it's just generating offsets of these instructions
好的，所以你可以看到编译器只是生成这些指令的偏移量
From the beginning of the .text section
从 .text 部分开始
And it includes this relocation entry which says to the linker hey
它包括这个重定位条目，它跟链接器打招呼
When you're relocating main.o add offset a in this .text section
当你重新定位 main.o 时，在此 .text 部分中添加偏移量 a
You've got a reference,a reference to an array in the form of a 32-bit address
你有一个 32 位地址形式的数组引用
Ok so that,so eventually the linker is going to have to patch up these
好的，那么，最终链接器将不得不修改它们
So this is address , this is address a
所以这是地址 a
It's going to have to patch up the four bytes starting at address a
它必须修改从地址 a 开始的四个字节
With the absolute address of the symbol array
地址 a 使用符号数组的绝对地址
And then similarly the reference to,the reference to,this the reference to this function sum
然后类似地引用这个函数的 sum
The compiler has no idea where sum actually will end up
编译器不知道 sum 实际上会在哪里结束
It doesn't even know what module it's in or even if it's, even if it is defined in a module
即使 sum 是在模块中定义的，编译器甚至不知道它所在的模块，甚至它是什么模块
So in this case it just it does a call with all zeros
所以在这种情况下它只能用全零来调用
And then it adds this relocation entry that says to the linker
然后它添加了对链接器通告的重定位条目
At offset f you've got a four byte pc-relative reference to a function,to assemble called sum
在偏移量 f 处，你有一个四字节的 pc 相对引用，用于汇总调用 sum
And then it this is sort of a arcane detail that but and it includes
然后，这有一个神奇的细节
There's an option to include a bias in the in the offset
可以选择在偏移中包含偏差
And since we're using since calls are always resolved using pc-relative addressing
因为我们正在使用，因为调用总是使用 pc 相对寻址来解决
The value that's going to be placed here at these four bytes that offset f
将在偏移 f 的四个字节处放置的值
Is going to be an offset from the current %rip value or program or counter value
将是当前 ％rip 值或程序或计数器值的偏移量
And since the program counter always points to the nest get next instruction
并且由于程序计数器总是指向嵌套获取下一条指令
It includes this which is four bytes away it includes this
它包括四个字节，它包括这个
This offset of minus four
这个偏移量减去四
So I talked about it in detail in the book if you really want to know how this works
所以如果你真的想知道它是如何工作的，我会在书中详细讨论它
But just the point here is that there's enough information for the linker to actually fill in the right address
但这里的重点是链接器有足够的信息来实际填充正确的地址
So now if we look at the relocated .text section
现在，如果我们查看重定位的 .text 部分
if we compile this code into an executable and then we use objdump to disassemble it
如果我们将此代码编译为可执行文件，然后我们使用 objdump 来反编译它
Then what you see is this reference here
那么你看到的就是这里的引用
Where we move the address of the address of a into %edi
我们将该地址传送到 ％edi
Those four bytes which were original zero have now been updated with the actual address of array in memory at runtime
这四个一开始为零的字节现在已经在运行时用内存中数组的实际地址更新
Okay so the linkers decided that the array is going to go at address 0x601018
好的，所以链接器决定数组将会在地址 0x601018 处
And then it's actually patched that the four bytes in the cup in the in the move instruction with that absolute address
然后它实际上修改了 mov 指令中该绝对地址中的四个字节
And the call to sum is...it's also been updated
对 sum 的调用是......它也被更新了
But this one's interesting right that
这很有趣
So the address it's been updated with the pc relative address of five
所以用 pc 的相对地址为 5 来更新它的地址
Okay so when this program runs
好的，所以当这个程序运行时
This call instruction
调用指令
What it will do when it when it determines when it computes the absolute address of the function sum
当它确定何时计算函数 sum 的绝对地址时它会做什么？
It will take...
他将
It will take the current value of the program counter which is the next instruction so 0x4004e3
它将采用程序计数器的当前值，即下一条指令 0x4004e3
And it will add to it whatever value is in this immediate field
它将增加它在这个区域的任何值
Okay which is a two's comp... interpret it as a two's complement integer so it can go
好的，这是一个二..把它解释为一个二进制补码整数，所以它可以
It can be relative you can go - or +
它可以是相对的，你可以去 - 或 +
In this case it's saying that the function that you want to call is at 0x4004e3 + 5
在这种情况下，它表示你要调用的函数是在 0x4004e3 + 5
Which is 0x4004e8 which is the address of sum
就是 0x4004e8，这是 sum 的地址
Okay and so the linker does that the compiler has all the smarts
好了，所以链接器做的是，编译器有这些智慧
The compiler computed the relocation entry
编译器计算了重定位条目
The linker is just blindly going through each of those relocation entries and just doing what it's told
链接器只是盲目地浏览每个重定位条目，只是按照它所说的去做
Okay but the next result is that now all of these these references have been patched up with valid absolute addresses
好的，但接下来的结果是，现在所有这些引用都已使用有效的绝对地址进行了修补
Now once the linkers created an object file
现在，一旦链接器创建了一个目标文件
That object file can be loaded the code and data
该对象文件可以加载代码和数据
And that object file can be loaded directly into memory with no further modification
并且该对象文件可以直接加载到内存中而无需进一步修改
Ok so the if you look at all of the read-only sections in the executable
好的，如果你查看可执行文件中的所有只读部分
So there's this .init section which
所以有这个 .init 部分
We're not to worry about that, all the code is in the .text and things like jump tables are in .rodata
我们不用担心，所有代码都在 .text 中，跳转表之类的东西都在 .rodata 中
All of this data can be loaded directly into memory as is
所有这些数据都可以直接加载到内存中
Okay so these bytes can just be copied directly into memory
好的，所以这些字节可以直接复制到内存中
And that forms the so called a read-only code segment
这形成了所谓的只读代码段
The data in the .data and .bss  sections can also be copied directly into memory
.data 和 .bss 部分中的数据也可以直接复制到内存中
And in the case of the variables and .data they'll be initialized to a value that's stored in the symbol table
在变量和 .data 的区域下，它们将被初始化为存储在符号表中的值
So we're drawing a memory here
所以我们在这里画一个存储模型
This is the (memory) address space that every Linux program sees
这是每个 Linux 程序看到的（内存）地址空间
And we're drawing addresses starting from 0 and going up increasing as we grow up
我们从 0 开始画地址，随着往上而增加
And every program is loaded at this the same address  0x400000
并且每个程序都加载到相同的地址 0x400000
And so the the code comes directly from the object file the data comes directly from the object file
因此代码直接来自目标文件，数据直接来自目标文件
And then that's followed by a runtime heap
然后是运行堆
Which is created and managed by malloc
这是由 malloc 创建和管理的
So when you need dynamically need to allocate memory
所以当你需要动态分配内存时
Like using malloc that memory comes out of this heap
比如使用 malloc ，内存来自这个堆
Which starts immediately following the data segment and grows upwards
它紧随数据段之后开始并向上发展
The stack is at the very top of the visible memory that's available to application programs
栈位于可见内存的最顶层，可供应用程序使用
The memory above that is restricted to the kernel
上面的内存仅限于内核
Okay so if you try to access those memory locations you'll get a seg fault
好的，如果你尝试访问这些内存位置，你将收到段错误
And then the stack as we know grows down so this is managed and created a runtime
然后我们知道的，堆栈会逐渐减少，这样就可以管理并创建一个运行时间
And then there's this region somewhere in this huge gap between the stack and the heap
然后在栈和堆之间的这个巨大差距将会在某个地方存在这个区域
There's a region for shared libraries so the .so files all get loaded into this memory-mapped region for shared libraries
共享库有一个区域，因此 .so 文件都被加载到共享库的内存映射区域
Now that the top of the heap is indicated by this global variable
现在堆的顶部由此全局变量指示
Maintained by the kernel called break brk
由内核维护，名为 break， brk
And the the top of the stack as we know is maintained by the general purpose register %rsp
我们所知道的堆栈顶部由通用寄存器 ％rsp 维护
Now there's a little bit of a...this is a little bit of a simplification
现在有一点......这有点简化
If you actually look at the addresses returned by malloc
如果你实际查看 malloc 返回的地址
There's actually,a there's actually two heaps
实际上，实际上有两个堆
There's a heap up here and in the high memory that grows down
这上面有一个堆，并且在高速记忆中会逐渐减少
That's used for large objects,very large
那用于大型目标，非常大
if you mount like a whole bunch of space
它会增长比如一大堆空间
And then the heap that grows up is  is reserved for smaller smaller objects
增长的堆被保留用于较小的目标
So I'm not really sure why they do this
所以我不确定他们为什么这样做
I think it allows them to have separate allocation algorithms for large objects and small objects
我认为它允许他们为大的目标和小的目标分别使用分配算法
Okay so one of the real advantages of linking is that allows us to create libraries of things
好吧接下来，链接的一个真正优势是允许我们创建库
So it's always something we want to do as programmers we always...
因此，作为程序员，我们总是希望做的某些事情......
We always want to create abstractions and then present those abstractions to users
我们总是希望创建抽象，然后将这些抽象呈现给用户
Right and we do that by creating libraries defining an api
是的，我们通过创建定义 api 的库来实现
Yes
是
[student speaking]
[学生说话]
I think it just is...no no it
我认为这只是......不，不
Actually that's a good question I... the things I've done it just grows until it runs out of memory right there
实际上，这是一个很好的问题，我...我做过的实验里面它会不断增长，直到它在那里耗尽内存
So I don't think actually that's a really good question I mean I've...
所以我认为这不认为....那是个一个非常好的问题我的意思是我...
I've done those experiments and it eventually reaches some limit
我做过那些实验，最终达到了一定的限度
Yeah I don't know it's a very large number
是的我不知道，这是一个非常大的数字
But I so you know as programmers we always want to abstract define apis
但我知道作为程序员我们总是想抽象定义 api
Implement package up those api's and make them available to to other programmers
实现打包这些 api 并将其提供给其他程序员
So how can we actually do that how can we make commonly used functions available to other programmers
那么我们如何才能真正实现这一目标呢？我们如何将常用函数提供给其他程序员
Well one thing given what we've learned so far
鉴于我们迄今为止学到的东西，还有一件事
You could just take all the functions and put them all in a single big C file right
你可以把所有的功能都放在一个大的 C 文件中
And then programmers would just link that C file into their programs if they want to use them right
如果他们想要正确使用它们然后程序员只要将 C 文件链接到他们的程序中
Another option would be to take that might get kind of unwieldy if it's a big library right
另一种选择是如果它是一个很大的库，可能会变得有点笨重
libc has hundreds and hundreds of functions
libc 有数百种功能
So another option would might be to just take each function put it in a separate file
所以另一种选择可能是将每个函数放在一个单独的文件中
And then compile them all together and compile and link them all together
然后将它们一起编译并编译并将它们链接在一起
So this is more space and time efficient than then the first option
因此，这比第一个选项更节省空间和时间
But it seems like it would be burdensome on the programmer because
但似乎这对程序员来说会很麻烦，因为
The program would have to know where all the all these functions were and put them in make files
该程序必须知道所有这些函数的位置，并将它们放在 make 文件中
It'd just be a lot of you know this you could end up with a ridiculously large command line to GCC
很多人都知道你最终可能会向 GCC 提供一个非常大的命令行
So that one solution to this problem is that
所以这个问题的一个解决方案是
The first solution that the developers of Unix came up with us
Unix 开发人员提出的第一个解决方案
Somebody called a static library
有些人称它为静态库
So the the idea where the static library is that you create this archive  called a .a file
因此，你创建了此被称为 .a 文件归档的静态库的想法
Which is it's just a collection of .o file where each .o file contains a function
这只是 .o 文件的集合，其中每个 .o 文件都包含一个函数
Ok so you take all the functions in your library you use option two to create a bunch of .o files
好的，所以你使用库中的所有函数，你使用选项二来创建一堆 .o 文件
And then you use a program called an archive or AR  to take those .o files
然后你使用一个名为 archive 或 AR 的程序来获取那些 .o 文件
Put them together in a all together in a big file called an archive
将它们放在一起，放在一个称为存档的大文件中
With a table of contents at the beginning that tells you the offset of each one of the .o files
开始使用一个内容目录，告诉你每个 .o 文件的偏移量
Ok so an archive is just this concatenated collection of .o files
好的，所以存档就是这个链接的 .o 文件集合
And then and then you link you pass that archive to the linker
然后，你将链接传递给链接器
And it only takes the .o files that are actually referenced  and links them into the code
它只需要实际引用的 .o 文件并将它们链接到代码中
Right so it's a more efficient way you can have a huge archive
这是一个更有效的方式，你可以有一个巨大的档案
But like libc but if you only call printf
但是比如 libc，但是如果你只调用 printf
The only .o file you get is printf.o
你得到的唯一 .o 文件是 printf.o
Okay so the way this works is
好的，这样做的方式是
As before we take
和以前采取的方式一样
We take all the functions we want to put in our library
我们将我们想要的所有函数放在库中
We run them through our translators to get .o files
我们通过翻译器运行它们来获取 .o 文件
We pass those to the archiver to get a the archive
我们将这些文件传递给归档器以获取归档文件
So in this case libc.a
所以在种情况下 libc.a
And which has this code for printf that we might want to use
可能有 printf 代码，我们想使用
Right and so we can recreate that archive anytime we want
是的，所以我们可以随时重新创建该档案
So if one of these functions changes like say printf changes
因此，如果其中一个函数发生变化，比如说 printf 更改
You just rearchive the dot recompile printf and then re archive all of the .o files
你只需重新存档....重新编译 printf，然后重新存档所有 .o 文件
So in libc it's about 1500 object files
在 libc 中它大约有 1500 个目标文件
And it's archived things like printf,scanf,simple integer math and there's also a math library
它存档的东西，比如 printf，scanf，简单的整数数学，还有一个数学库
Which has you know several hundred common functions for things like
你知道几百种常见功能
Floating point math sin,cos,tan gent etc
比如浮点数学 sin，cos，tan 等
These libraries the convention is that a library always is prefixed with lib with lib and then
这些库的惯例是，库总是以 lib 为前缀，然后
And then sort of new some indication of what it what it does
然后对它的作用进行了一些额外暗示
So now let's see how linking with these static libraries would work
现在让我们看看如何与这些静态库链接起作用
So I've created a little example here
所以我在这里创建了一个小例子
I've created a library called libvector.a
我创建了一个名为 libvector.a 的库
And it consists of functions that manipulate vectors
它由操纵向量的函数组成
And this is a real simple library it just adds
这是一个真正简单只是加的库
There's a function to add two vectors x and y together and return the result in z
这里有一个函数可以将两个向量 x 和 y 相加并在 z 中返回结果
And then another similar function that will do pairwise multiplication of two vectors so
然后是另一个类似的函数，它将对两个向量进行成对乘法
x[i]*y[i] equals z[i]
x [i] * y [i] 等于 z [i]
Now I compile these two programs and pack I want to package them into an archive called libvector.a
现在我编译这两个程序并打包，我想将它们打包成一个名为 libvector.a 的存档
And then in my main program I'm going to call one of those functions addvec
然后在我的主程序中，我将调用其中一个函数 addvec
To add these two vectors x and y together
将这两个向量 x 和 y 加在一起
So now what happens when we compile this this program
那么现在当我们编译这个程序时会发生什么
We've already we've constructed the archive libc.a  from addvec.o and multvec.o
我们已经从 addvec.o 和 multvec.o 构建了存档 libc.a
And we pass that archive to the linker along with a main2.o relocatable object file
我们将该存档与 main.o 可重定位目标文件一起传递给链接器
And we also pass it libc.a
我们也将它传递给 libc.a
Which has the definition of which contains printf.o
其定义包含 printf.o
And anything else that printf.o my call
剩下的就是调用 printf.o
So these three the linker detects the reference to addvec the function addvec
所以这三个链接器检测到 addvec 函数 addvec 的引用
And so it just pulls addvec.o out and ignores the rest,similarly for printf.o
所以它只是将 addvec.o 拉出来并忽略其余部分，类似于 printf.o
And then it compiles all those
然后它编译所有这些
Main main.o addvec.o and printf.o all together into this fully linked executable
主要的 main.o addvec.o 和 printf.o 一起进入这个完全链接的可执行文件
Called prog2c for compile-time
称为 prog2c 编译时间
So we're doing this,we're doing this link,we're doing this this linking at compile time
所以我们这样做，我们正在做这个链接，我们在编译时这样做这个链接
When we call a GCC
当我们调用 GCC 时
Now what the linker does when it's using static libraries
现在链接器在使用静态库时会做什么
It scans all the .o files and .a files in order on the command line
它在命令行上按顺序扫描所有 .o 文件和 .a 文件
So you're just typing GCC and then a list of .o files and .a files in some order
因此，你只需键入 GCC，然后按某种顺序键入 .o 文件和 .a 文件列表
So during the scan it keeps a list of the current unresolved references right
因此，在扫描期间，它会保留当前未解析的引用列表
If let's say let's say it looks at main.o first and there's a reference to printf
如果我们说它首先会看看 main.o 有一个对 printf 的引用
That's an unresolved reference because printf is not defined in main.o
这是一个未解析的引用，因为 printf 未在 main.o 中定义
So that goes in a list of undefined references
所以这是一个未定义的引用列表
And at some point or another as each new .o file or .a file is encountered
在某些时候，每个新的 .o 文件或 .a 文件会冲突
The linker tries to without but list of references with the symbols that are defined in that .o file or .a file
链接器尝试使用该 .o 文件或 .a 文件中定义的符号但不包含引用列表
And then if there's any entries in the list at the end of the scan then there's error
然后，如果在扫描结束时列表中有任何条目，那么就会出错
Okay so that the key here is that the linker will try to resolve these references from left to right on the command line
好的，这里的关键是链接器将尝试在命令行上从左到右解析这些引用
And so this is another sort of important thing for you to know as programmers
因此，作为程序员，这是另一种重要的事情
Because the order that you put your files on the command line actually makes a difference
因为你将文件放在命令行上的顺序实际上有所不同
Okay so you can get sort of weird baffling linker errors if you use the wrong order
好的，如果你使用错误的顺序，你可能会遇到一些奇怪的令人困惑的链接器错误
So for instance suppose we've got
所以比如假设我们有
A function an object module called libtest
一个函数，一个名为 libtest 的对象模块
That calls a function that's defined in lmine.a
它调用了一个在 lmine.a 中定义的函数
Okay so these -L., -L. period that says to look for,to look for a library files in the current directory
好的，所以这些 -L，-L 要求查找，以查找当前目录中的库文件
That's what the dot look there first and then look in the normal places that you look
这就是查找的点，然后查找你看起来正常的地方
And the the -l that's a it's like an abbreviation
而 -l 就像是一个缩写
We could replace this with just the fully spelled out lmind.a
我们可以用完全拼写的 lmind.a 替换它
Okay but you'll see this this  -l used a lot
好的，但是你会看到这个 -l 我经常使用它
So libtest calls a function that's declared in lmind.a
libtest 调用了在 lmind.a 中声明的函数
So the linker looks at it looks at the unresolved symbols in libtest.o
因此，链接器会查看 libtest.o 中未解析的符号
And it detects that there's this unresolved function let's say it's called foo
并且它检测到这个未解析的函数，我们称它为 foo
I know its， it's called libfun
我知道它，叫做 libfun
So and it puts it on the list and then it goes on to the next command line entry and that's lmine.a
所以它把它放在列表上然后继续下一个命令行条目，也就是 lmine.a
And in there it finds it finds this symbol of libfun
在那里，它发现它找到了 libfun 的这个符号
And it resolves the reference to that libfun to the actual address the relocated address
并且它将对 libfun 的引用解析为重定位地址的实际地址
Now if we switch the order and we put lmine.a first followed by libtest.o
现在，如果我们切换顺序，我们首先将 lmine.a 放在 libtest.o 之前
Well there's no unresolved references in this library
那么这个库中就没有未解析的引用
Right it's just the collection of function definitions
对，它只是函数定义的集合
So it there's no unresolved references so the linker looks at that that's all good
因此它没有未解析的引用，因此链接器会发现这一切都很好
And then it looks at libtest.o and now there's an unresolved reference to to libfun
然后它查看 libtest.o，现在 libfun 有未解析的引用
But we're out of we're at the end of the command line
但是我们已经到了命令行的末尾
So that's a linker error
所以就有了一个链接器错误
So you get this you get this really cryptic error message
所以你获取了这个神秘的错误信息
And if you didn't know about this ordering rule you wouldn't have any idea how to debug
如果你不了解此顺序规则，你将不知道如何调试
It okay so the static libraries are kind of the old fashioned solution that
没关系，静态库是一种老式的解决方案
The modern solution is to use dynamic libraries or shared libraries
现代解决方案是使用动态库或共享库
So the reason the reason there's this sort of newer form of libraries
这种新型库的存在是有原因的
That static libraries have some disadvantages
静态库有一些缺点
So every if you compile with static libraries
所以如果你用静态库编译的话
Then every every function that uses printf
然后每个使用 printf 的函数
Which or every program that uses printf has to have a copy of printf
使用 printf 的那个或每个程序都必须有 printf 的副本
Okay but almost every every program uses printf right
好的，但几乎每个程序都使用 printf
So there's a shared libraries allow provide a mechanism where there can just be one
共享库允许提供一个机制，这种机制使得其只能有一个
Wherever there's just one instance of a shared library member like printf
只能有一个像 printf 这样的共享库成员的实例
And every program running on the system will share that one copy
并且系统上运行的每个程序都将共享该副本
So that's sort of the big disadvantage is this potential duplication
那种潜在的重复是一个很大的缺点
So shared libraries are different in the sense that they contain
共享库的意义是不同的
Code and data that are linked and loaded into the program now when it's
他们包含链接并加载进程序的代码和数据
Now when it's compiled and linked and into a executable object file
现在是编译和链接到可执行目标文件时
But actually when the program is loaded into the system
但实际上当程序加载到系统中时
So linking of references to shared library objects is deferred
对共享库对象的引用的链接延迟了
Until the program is actually loaded into memory
直到程序实际加载到内存中
Until the executable object file is actually loaded into memory
直到可执行目标文件实际加载到内存中
And this can either and it can even happen
这也可以，甚至可能发生
It can happen when the program is actually loaded into memory but it can also happen at runtime anytime at runtime
它可能在程序实际加载到内存时发生，但也可以在运行时随时在运行时发生
So you can be...you can be running a program
所以你可以...你可以运行一个程序
And that program can arbitrarily decide to load a function that's declared in a shared library
并且该程序可以任意决定加载在共享库中声明的函数
Okay and I'll show you that it's really cool
好的，我会告诉你它真的很酷
Now these things are often called they're called shared libraries
现在这些东西经常被称为共享库
They're called dynamic link libraries like in windows they're called dlls
它们被称为动态链接库，比如在 windows 中，它们被称为 dll
.so files they're all referenced the same thing
.so 文件，他们都引用了相同的东西
Okay so that this like I said you can...
好吧这就像我说的那样......
The dynamic linking can occur when the program's loaded or after it's loaded and actually running
动态链接可以在程序加载时或在加载后实际运行时发生
And there's this sort of big deal that shared library routines can be shared by multiple processes
并且存在这样一个了不起的事，共享库例程可以由多个进程共享
And we'll look at this this will make sense when we look at virtual memories
当我们学习到虚拟内存时，我们就会发现这是有意义的
So don't worry about that now
所以现在不要担心
But but here's how the process works
这就是流程如何工作的图
So we've,first we have to create instead of creating an archive
所以我们首先要创建而不是创建存档
We create a shared library,so our libvector routines
我们创建一个共享库，我们的 libvector 程序
Instead of creating an archive a file we create a shared a .so file
我们创建一个共享的 .so 文件，而不是创建存档文件
Using the shared argument to GCC
使用 GCC 的共享参数
So we take our two input functions a addvec and multvec
因此我们将两个输入函数作为 addvec 和 multvec
And share it says to create and we're telling GCC to create a shared library  and place it in libvector.so
并告诉它说要创建，我们告诉 GCC 创建一个共享库并将其放在 libvector.so 中
Okay and so and there's also that the C developers have created a shared library called libc.so
好的，还有 C 开发人员创建了一个名为 libc.so 的共享库
That contains printf and on it and other standard library functions
它包含 printf 和其他标准库函数
So we take our program main2,this is the same program that calls addvec
所以我们采用我们的程序 main2 ，这是调用 addvec 的相同程序
And we compile it into main2.o
我们将它编译成 main2.o
And we pass main2.o and  these .so files to the linker
我们将 main2.o 和这些 .so 文件传递给链接器
Now the linker doesn't at this point it doesn't actually copy that say we're using addvec or printf
现在链接器在实际上并没有真的复制我们将要使用的 addvec 或 printf
It doesn't actually copy those functions or do anything with them in the executable
它实际上并不复制这些函数或在可执行文件中对它们执行任何操作
It just makes a note in the symbol table that those functions will need to be the
它只是在符号表中记下一笔
References to those functions will need to be resolved when the program is loaded
加载程序时需要解析对这些函数的引用
Okay so it,it puts in a relocation entry that says fix this up when you load the program
好吧，它放入一个重定位条目，说明在加载程序时解决这个问题
So it's partially linked but it's not fully linked
所以它是部分链接的，但它并没有完全链接起来
You can't take that,you can't take a program,you can't take a executable file
你不能获取那个，你不能获取一个程序，你不能获取一个可执行文件
That was dynamically linked and loaded directly
这就是动态链接和直接加载
What you do is the loader which is the execve system call
你所做的是作为 execve 系统调用的加载器
And we'll learn more about that, but just this is just a sys call that loads loads executables into memory and runs them
我们将更多地了解它，但这只是一个 sys 调用，它将可执行文件加载到内存中并运行它们
The loader takes the executable
加载器获取可执行文件
And then it takes the shared .so files
然后它需要共享的 .so 文件
That this program needs k it also made when the linker also made a note of which .so files it needs
当链接器还记录了它需要哪个 .so 文件时，这个程序还需要 k
So the loader calls the dynamic linker which takes those .so files
所以加载器调用动态链接器，它接受那些 .so 文件
And then actually resolves all the references to any on any unresolved reference
然后实际解析任何未解析的引用上的所有引用
Okay so the the address of addvec,the addvec and printf functions isn't determined until the program is loaded
好的，所以 addvec 的地址，addvec 和 printf 函数在程序加载之前是不确定的
And by that and it isn't determined by the dynamic linker until the program is loaded
由此，在加载程序之前，动态链接器不会确定它
So that the dynamic linker does it goes through a similar process that the static linker did
因此，动态链接器会执行与静态链接器类似的过程
Sort of fixing up references to add back at references to printf
修复引用以加回对 printf 的引用
And then at that point the binary is in a form that can be executed directly
然后在那时，二进制文件的形式可以直接执行
So question-yes-what if you look the part where did like where is that like if you include violence and use anger and greed zero actually
你有问题？ - 是 -------
Okay the question is what happens if you include a file
好的问题是如果使用 include 了一个文件会发生什么
So includes are handled by the C preprocessor
includes 是由 C 预处理器处理
So they're gone, they're long gone, by the time the by the time the linker gets around to it
因此，当链接器到达它时，它们已经处理过了
Okay so the C preprocessor just takes #define,#include
好的，所以 C 预处理器只需要 #define，#include
And and interprets those and outputs another C program
并解释这些并输出另一个 C 程序
So if you include a file the C preprocessor just takes that file and just expands it
因此，如果你 include 一个文件， C 预处理器只需要获取该文件并将其扩展
And the output C program contains an expanded version of all the files that you include it
输出 C 程序包含你 include 它的所有文件的扩展版本
Okay now that's really cool is that you can also do this dynamic linking at runtime
好的，现在真正酷的是你也可以在运行时进行动态链接
So what I showed you before we're doing it at load time
所以我要向你展示加载时候发生了什么
But you can also arbitrarily decide to load link and call a function from a shared from a from any function defined in a .so file
但你也可以随意决定加载链接并从 .so 文件中定义的任何共享函数中调用函数
And the way you do it is there's a there's an interface called the dlopen
你这样做的方法是有一个名为 dlopen 的接口
That's in lib.c that allows you to do this
这是在 lib.c 中允许你这样做
So let's say we want to this is our main program and just like before we want to call addvec
所以，我们希望这是我们的主程序，就像我们之前想要调用 addvec 的那样
Okay but addvec now is defined in a .so file
好的，但现在 addvec 是在 .so 文件中定义的
The exact same .so file that we generated before
我们之前生成的完全相同的 .so 文件
When we compile,so we'll call this dll.c,when we compile this program ddl.c
当我们编译时，所以当我们编译这个程序 dll.c 时，我们将调用这个 dll.c
We have no idea that it's going to call a function from lib.so
我们不知道它会从 lib.so 调用一个函数
We just compile it as though a standalone C program
我们只是编译它就像是编译一个独立的 C 程序
Within this program though we declare a pointer a function pointer called addvec
虽然我们在这个程序中声明了一个名为 addvec 的函数指针
And we give the prototype for this function
我们给出了这个函数的原型
It's pointers .. so it's a two input arrays, the output array on the size
它是指针，它有两个输入数组，还有的关于规模的输出数组
And then first we dynamically load the shared library that contains the function we want
然后我们首先动态加载包含我们想要的函数的共享库
So we call dlopen and we say load up this .so file into memory
然后我们调用 dlopen，然后我们说把这个 .so 文件加载到内存中
So that I can call a function
这样我就可以调用一个函数了
But don't resolve,you know don't worry about the resolving the references to it functions until I actually tell you to
但是不要解析.....不要担心解析函数引用，直到告诉你要去才去
That's the lazy part
那是 LAZY 的部分
And so what what this deal open returns a handle
那么这个处理返回了一个 handle
That then you use in subsequent calls okay
然后用在随后的调用中
So if we don't if the handle is null there was some kind of error like maybe this data .so file doesn't exist
如果 handle 为空，就会出现某种错误，例如这个 .so 文件并不存在
So once we've opened that .so file then we use dlsym with the handle so this
所以一旦我们打开那个 .so 文件，我们就会使用带有 handle 参数的 dlsym 函数
And then we give it as we pass as a string the name of the function that we want to invoke
然后我们给它，因为我们传递一个字符串作为我们想要调用的函数的名称
And what we get back from dlsym as a pointer to that function
我们得到从 dlsym 返回参数作为指向该函数的指针
And then we can use that function just like any other function so we can use that function pointer
然后我们可以像任何其他函数一样使用该函数，因此我们可以使用该函数指针
And we call it just as though it were a statically defined function
我们称之为静态定义函数
So you can see this is real very powerful technique
所以你可以看到这是一个非常强大的技术
Okay so looks let's finish the last little bits of the class
好吧看起来让我们完成课程的最后一点
I want to show you it to try to convince you that linking is is actually interesting which is kind of a hard sell sometime
我想告诉你它试图说服你，链接实际上是有趣的，好像是在硬形推销一样
Yes question...yes...no it's that's how you know
好的问题......是的......不
No you just it's declared as a function pointer
不，你只是声明它是一个函数指针
And you then you just use the name of the function you don't have to dereference it
然后你就可以使用你没有的函数名称来取消引用它
Or you just you call it you call the function by just using that function pointer name okay
或者你只是在调用它，你只需使用该函数指针名称即可调用该函数
Just like I did
就像我一样
If you dereference it I just get back a pointer value
如果你取消引用它我只是得到一个指针值
You get back the address of that function
你得到那个函数返回的地址
All right so it's kind of a hard sell to that to convince you that linking is interesting
好吧，硬性推销给你们说链接很有意思感觉很难
But I'm going to try
但是我要试试
Ok so there's this powerful technique called inner library inter positioning
好的，有一种强大的技术称为库打桩
And the goal is to intercept function calls from libraries
目标是截获来自库的函数调用
And do something intercept them for some reason
以及出于某种原因截获它们后做一些事情
Right so what we typically want to do is intercept a function call
我们通常想要做的就是截获一个函数调用
Maybe record some to some statistics or do some error checking
也许记录一些统计数据或做一些错误检查
And then call the real function as intended
然后按预期调用实际函数
Right so the idea is we're going to create wrappers
对，所以我们的想法是创建包装函数
And when the program when a program calls a function what we're going to do is we're going to execute its wrapper instead
当一个程序调用一个函数的程序时，我们要做的就是执行它的包装函数
Okay and we're going to do it without changing any of the source
好的，我们将在不改变任何源的情况下这样做
Now there's a lot of reasons there's a lot of applications for this
现在有很多原因这样做，有很多应用程序
That the neatest one that I know is that these facebook engineers
我知道的最棒的是 facebook 工程师做过的
So we're trying to deal with this year-long bug in the facebook iPhone app
他们正试图在 Facebook 的 iPhone 应用程序中解决一个长达一年的错误
And nobody could figure out what was going on
没有人能弄明白发生了什么
And they figured it out using library inter positioning
他们使用库间定位来解决这个问题
They figured out that there was something in the network stack writing to the wrong location
他们发现网络栈中有东西写错了位置
They figured it out by intercepting all the calls from their facebook app  that did rights
他们通过拦截来自他们的 Facebook 应用程序的所有权限来解决这个问题
So things like write to the ep right
然后做一些处理比如写入权限
So they just they intercepted all those calls and then they were able to
他们只是拦截了所有这些电话，然后他们就可以
To when they looked at the arguments and how those functions were being called
当他们查看参数以及如何调用这些函数时
They determine the air
他们决定
You can also use it for monitoring and profiling like
你也可以使用它进行监视和分析
So if you want to know like how many times different functions get called you can you can interpose
因此，如果你想知道调用不同函数的次数，你可以设置
We use it for generating address traces
我们用它来生成地址追踪
So you're malloc when you do your malloc lab later in the semester
所以当你在学期后期做 malloc 实验时
You're going to be evaluating your malloc using a traces
你将使用追踪程序评估你的 malloc
That we generated from real programs using this inter positioning technique
这种追踪程序是从使用了库打桩技术的真实程序中生成的
Right so we interpose on all the malloc and free calls in like netscape
我们插入所有 malloc 和free 调用，比如 netscape
And then we just recorded what addresses and sizes
然后我们只记录了地址和大小
Malloc was returning and what what blocks free was freeing up
Malloc 返回后，free 块释放了
And we just created a trace of those, and then, so let me show you how you would do this
我们刚刚创建了那些追踪程序，然后，让我告诉你如何做到这一点
So the idea let's say we have this main program
所以有个主意，这里有一个主程序
And the idea is to trace all the malloc and free calls
我们的想法是跟踪所有 malloc 和 free 调用
So there's one malloc call and there's one free call
所以这里有一个 malloc 调用，以及下面调用了 free
And we want to know what these addresses are and we want to know what these sizes are
我们想知道这些地址是什么，我们想知道这些大小是什么
So we can do this at either compile time, link time or run time
所以我们可以在编译时，链接时或运行时执行库打桩操作
To do it at compile time
在编译时执行此操作
We first write wrapper functions called mymalloc and myfree
我们首先编写名为 mymalloc 和 myfree 的包装函数
Where mymalloc calls the __real_malloc function
mymalloc 能在相应的位置调用 __real_malloc 函数
And then it prints out the the size that it was called and the address that malloc returned
然后它打印出它它调用的大小和 malloc 返回的地址
Okay so this when we run our program it will print out these all these addresses
好的，所以当我们运行程序时，它会打印出这些所有这些地址
And it does the same thing for free
并且它免费做同样的事情
And then here's the trick in malloc.h
然后是 malloc.h 中的技巧
We define malloc to be mymalloc ,okay and free to be myfree
我们将 malloc 定义为 mymalloc，好的，并且把 free 定义为 myfree
And then we give the prototype for it so the compiler doesn't get confused
然后我们给它原型，这样编译器就不会混淆了
And then we can compile mymalloc.c into a .o file
然后我们可以将 mymalloc.c 编译成 .o 文件
And then we call... then we complete we call our program
然后我们调用....然后我们完成我们调用程序
Which is our main program int.c for inner positioning
这是我们用于库打桩的主要程序 int.c
And we call that and here's the trick
我们调用它，这里有个诀窍
We call it with the -I argument
我们用 -I 参数调用它
And we say look for any include files in the current directory
它的意思是在当前目录中查找任何 include 文件
Okay so this was similar to that -L argument
好的，这与 -L 参数类似
But because we tell GCC to look in the current directory first
但是因为我们告诉 GCC 要先查看当前目录
So this is sort of where the inner positioning happens
这可以说就是库打桩发生的地方
This because when it does that it's going to it's going to find a
这是因为当它这样做时，它会找到一个
It's going to find a library called malloc.h
它将找到一个名为 malloc.h 的库
I mean .h file called malloc.h
我的意思是 .h 文件叫做 malloc.h
And so all the calls to malloc will be translated by the C preprocessor to mymalloc
所以对 malloc 的所有调用都将由 C 预处理器转换为 mymalloc
So when we run this it prints out the the tri... malloc and free trace
因此，当我们运行它时，它打印出 malloc 和 free 的跟踪信息
Now we can also do this at link time
现在我们也可以在链接时执行此操作
So we can tell C,in order to do this we had to get access to the
所以我们可以告诉 C，为了做到这一点，我们必须访问
We had to compile the program,we didn't have to change it but we had to compile it
我们必须编译程序，我们不必更改它，但我们必须编译它
We can use link time at our positioning if to avoid that compilation
如果要避免编译，我们可以在定位时使用链接时间
So the way this works we define our wrapper functions with this special name __wrap_malloc
因此，我们使用这个特殊名称 __wrap_malloc 来定义我们的包装函数
And this calls the __real_malloc function and then prints out the information
这会调用 __real_malloc 函数，然后打印出信息
And then at link time then we do the inter positioning by calling the linker with this special -Wl  argument
然后在链接时，我们通过使用这个特殊的 -Wl 参数调用链接器来进行打桩
And so what this does the -Wl flag to GCC says hey
那么 GCC 的 -Wl 标志是什么呢
Take what follows the argument that follows replace all the commas with spaces
接下来的参数后面用逗号替换所有空格
And then invoke the linker with this argument
然后使用此参数调用链接器
Okay so what we're doing is passing a linker arguments to the linker
好的，我们正在做的是将链接器参数传递给链接器
And this --wrap argument to the linker
这是链接器的 --wrap 参数
It tells the linker to resolve all references to malloc as __wrap_malloc
它告诉链接器将对 malloc 的所有引用解析为 __wrap_malloc
And all references to __real_malloc - should be resolved as malloc
并且对 __real_malloc 的所有引用  - 应该被解析为 malloc
Okay so anywhere in the program what we call malloc it'll be resolved to underscore __wrap_malloc
好的，在我们程序中的任何地方调用 malloc ，它都将被解析为 __wrap_malloc
And it will invoke our wrapper and then the wrapper calls __real_malloc
它将调用我们的包装器，然后包装器调用 __real_malloc
Which by because of this flag resolves to the the actual malloc routine
因为这个标志解析了实际的 malloc 例程
Now here you can also in the really the really amazing thing
真正令人惊讶的是接下来的
You can also do this inter positioning it load timer and run time when the program is loaded
你也可以在加载程序时进行打桩到加载计时器和运行时间
So you don't even need access to the .o files all you need is access to the executable
因此，你甚至不需要访问 .o 文件，只需访问可执行文件即可
Right and for every program we have access to the executable
我们有权访问可执行文件的每个程序
So think about that we can take any program
所以想想我们可以使用任何程序
And we can interpose on its library calls at runtime
我们可以在运行时插入其库调用
So the way we do this is we write the wrapper function now uses the dlsym call that we saw before
所以我们这样做的原因是我们编写包装函数使用了我们之前看到的 dlsym 调用
And we call it with this special function the special argument called next
我们用这个特殊的函数调用它，这个特殊的参数叫做 next
And we silver and what this is saying is get the address of the real malloc
我们说的是 real malloc 的地址
Okay so and we're going to trick the linker into looking first to implementation of malloc
好的，我们将欺骗链接器首先查看 malloc 的实现
But here we want the real one,so we're telling it to get to look in the next place,its next place that it would normally look
但是在这里我们想要真正的那个，所以我们告诉它要去下一个地方，它通常看起来的下一个地方
And fetch the the address of malloc
并获取 malloc 的地址
So the result is a pointer a function pointer called mallocp
所以结果是一个指针叫做 mallocp 的函数指针
And then we can just call that function to get to call the libc malloc
然后我们可以调用该函数来调用 libc malloc
And then print out the the data
然后打印出数据
Okay we do the same thing for free, we use dlsym in exactly the same way for free
好的，我们对 free 做同样的事情，我们以完全相同的方式对 free 使用 dlsym
And then the inter positioning now happens when the program is loaded
然后，当程序加载时，就会发生打桩
So notice we built this our main program now intr for run time inter positioning
所以请注意，我们构建了我们的主程序 intr ，用于运行时打桩
We built it I'm sorry we created our .so file mymalloc.so using the shared argument
我们建立了，很抱歉我们使用共享参数创建了我们的 .so 文件 mymalloc.so
And then we compiled int.c into this executable called intr
然后我们将 int.c 编译成这个名为 intr 的可执行文件
But notice there's no mention of mymalloc.so anywhere
但请注意，在任何地方都没有提到 mymalloc
And now the inner positioning happens when we actually run the program
现在，当我们实际运行程序时，打桩就会发生
And we do it,we affect the the inner positioning by setting an environment variable called ld-preload to mymalloc.so
我们这样做，我们通过将一个名为 ld-preload 的环境变量设置为 mymalloc.so 来影响打桩
And so what this is a environment variable that tells the dynamic linker
这是一个告诉动态链接器的环境变量
To look first in the value, it looked first in the the value of ld-preload is a list of locations
首先会搜索值， ld-preload 的值是一个位置列表
Look first in those locations when to resolve references
首先查看这些位置何时解析引用
And only later look in the normal system places
只有在以后查看正常系统的地方
So we're saying to look in mymalloc.so unresolved references first
所以我们首先要查看 mymalloc.so 里未解析的引用
And then we're invoking,so this is in bash this is how you initialize an environment variable
然后我们正在调用，所以这是在 bash 中这是初始化环境变量的方式
So we're initializing it to mymalloc.so and then we're loading and running the program
所以我们将它初始化为 mymalloc.so 然后我们将加载并运行该程序
And so the ld so all the references to malloc get turned into the references to the wrapper function
所以对 malloc 的所有引用都变成了对包装函数的引用
The malloc function that we defined in our program okay
我们在程序中定义的 malloc 函数没问题
Ok so that's it so that that inter positioning is a really cool technique
好的就是这样，这样的定位是一种非常酷的技术
And it's only possible because of linkers so
而且只有因为链接器才有可能
alright so good we'll see you on on Thursday and good luck with your cache labs
好的，我们星期四见，祝你的 cache lab 好运